{
  "data": [
    {
      "question": "Who is the directed of Avtar ?",
      "option": ["Steven Spielberg", "James Cameron", "Martin Scorsese"],
      "correctAnswer": "James Cameron",
      "id": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the highest grossing movie in Hollywood ?",
      "option": ["Avatar", "Avengers", "Titanic"],
      "correctAnswer": "Avengers",
      "id": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the alter ego of Batman called ?",
      "option": ["Bruce Wayne", "Clerk Kent", "Bruce Banner"],
      "correctAnswer": "Bruce Wayne",
      "id": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "Who was the first Black person to win an Oscar?",
      "option": ["Hattie McDaniel", "Sidney Poitier", "James Earl Jones"],
      "correctAnswer": "Hattie McDaniel",
      "id": 4
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of the fictional land where Frozen takes place?",
      "option": ["Florin", "Arendelle", "Naples"],
      "correctAnswer": "Arendelle",
      "id": 5
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of these actors has never won an oscar",
      "option": ["Leonardo Dicaprio", "Lupita Nyongo", "Samuel L. Jackson"],
      "correctAnswer": "Samuel L. Jackson",
      "id": 6
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the dying words of Charles Foster Kane in Citizen Kane?",
      "option": ["I love you", "Rosebud", "I will be back"],
      "correctAnswer": "Rosebud",
      "id": 7
    },
    {
      "question": "What was the first feature-length animated movie ever released?",
      "option": [
        "Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs",
        "The Lion King",
        "Mickey Mouse"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs",
      "id": 8
    },
    {
      "question": "In The Matrix, does Neo take the blue pill or the red pill?",
      "option": ["Blue", "Red", "Neither"],
      "correctAnswer": "Red",
      "id": 9
    },
    {
      "question": "What's the name of the skyscraper in Die Hard?",
      "option": ["Nakatomi Plaza", "LA Plaza", "Pent House Plaza"],
      "correctAnswer": "Nakatomi Plaza",
      "id": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "What American writer/director starred in several iconic European-produced \"Spaghetti Westerns\"?",
      "option": ["Martin Scorsese", "Clint Eastwood", "Quentin Tarantino"],
      "correctAnswer": "Clint Eastwood",
      "id": 11
    },
    {
      "question": "In what 1976 thriller does Robert De Niro famously say \"You talkin' to me?\"",
      "option": ["The Godfather", "Taxi Driver", "The Casino"],
      "correctAnswer": "Taxi Driver",
      "id": 12
    },
    {
      "question": "For what movie did Steven Spielberg win his first Oscar for Best Director?",
      "option": ["Jaws", "Schindler's List", "Saving Private Ryan"],
      "correctAnswer": "Schindler's List",
      "id": 13
    },
    {
      "question": "Who directed Parasite – the first foreign-language film to win the Academy Award for Best Picture?",
      "option": ["Bong Joon-ho", "John Woo", "Kim Jee-woon"],
      "correctAnswer": "Bong Joon-ho",
      "id": 14
    },
    {
      "question": "What Hollywood movie star plays himself in Zombieland?",
      "option": ["Samuel L. Jackson", "Bill Murray", "Amber Heard"],
      "correctAnswer": "Bill Murray",
      "id": 15
    },
    {
      "question": "In 2013, Lupita Nyong'o became the first Kenyan and Mexican actress to win an Academy Award – which film did she win it for?",
      "option": ["Queen of Katwe", "Us", "12 Years A Slave"],
      "correctAnswer": "12 Years A Slave",
      "id": 16
    },
    {
      "question": "For which 1964 musical blockbuster did Julie Andrews win the Academy Award for Best Actress?",
      "option": ["The Sound Of Music", "Cinderella", "Mary Poppins"],
      "correctAnswer": "Mary Poppins",
      "id": 17
    },
    {
      "question": "Which movie was incorrectly announced as the winner of Best Picture at the 2017 Academy Awards, during the greatest Oscars flub of all time?",
      "option": ["Get Out", "Wonder", "La La Land"],
      "correctAnswer": "La La Land",
      "id": 18
    },
    {
      "question": "Aaron Sorkin won an Oscar for writing what 2010 drama about the creation of Facebook?",
      "option": ["Shutter Island", "Money Ball", "The Social Network"],
      "correctAnswer": "The Social Network",
      "id": 19
    },
    {
      "question": "Joaquin Phoenix received his first Oscar nomination for playing Roman emperor Commodus in what 2000 Oscar-winning epic?",
      "option": ["Gladiator", "The Yards", "The Master"],
      "correctAnswer": "Gladiator",
      "id": 20
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the title of the first film in the Fast and Furious franchise?",
      "option": [
        "2 Fast 2 Furious",
        "The Fast and The Furious",
        "The Turbo Charged"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "The Fast and The Furious",
      "id": 21
    },
    {
      "question": "what was the last fast and furious film, Paul Walker appeared in before his passing  in 2015 ?",
      "option": ["Fast Five", "Furious 7", "Fast & Furious 6"],
      "correctAnswer": "Furious 7",
      "id": 22
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of these movies is starring Heath Ledger ?",
      "option": [
        "The Dark Knight Rises",
        "A Knight's Tale",
        "Gone in 60 Seconds"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "A Knight's Tale",
      "id": 23
    },
    {
      "question": "The Battle of Thermopylae served as the basis of what highly stylized 2006 smash hit swords-and-sandals action flick?",
      "option": ["Apocalypto", "300", "Prince of Persia"],
      "correctAnswer": "300",
      "id": 24
    },
    {
      "question": "Which Alfred Hitchcock thriller is notorious for its shocking \"shower scene\"?",
      "option": ["Rear Window", "To Catch a Thief", "Psycho"],
      "correctAnswer": "Psycho",
      "id": 25
    },
    {
      "question": "Three of Jim Carrey's blockbusters—The Mask, Dumb and Dumber and Ace Ventura: Pet Detective—were all released in what year?",
      "option": ["1994", "1995", "1996"],
      "correctAnswer": "1994",
      "id": 26
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is the first and only woman of color to win the Oscar for Best Actress?",
      "option": ["Viola Davis", "Halley Berry", "Angela Bassett"],
      "correctAnswer": "Halley Berry",
      "id": 27
    },
    {
      "question": "Which movie character is associated with the phrase \"I drink and I know things\" ?",
      "option": ["The Godfather", "Tyrion Lannister", "Tywin Lannister"],
      "correctAnswer": "Tyrion Lannister",
      "id": 28
    },
    {
      "question": "In which animated fantasy film is the following dialogue from ?\n\"Give him a gold piece and send him home, he has a story to tell ...\"",
      "option": ["Afro Sumurai", "Beowulf", "Soul"],
      "correctAnswer": "Beowulf",
      "id": 29
    },
    {
      "question": "How many Oscars has Meryl Streep won?",
      "option": ["1", "2", "3"],
      "correctAnswer": "3",
      "id": 30
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of Riley's imaginary friend in Inside Out?",
      "option": ["Toto", "Bing Bong", "Luna"],
      "correctAnswer": "Bing Bong",
      "id": 32
    },
    {
      "question": "What internationally esteemed Malaysian actress has starred in a Bond film, Crouching Tiger, Hidden Dragon, Crazy Rich Asians, Shang-Chi and the Legend of the Ten Rings and more?",
      "option": ["Michelle Chen", "Michelle Lee", "Michelle Yeoh"],
      "correctAnswer": "Michelle Yeoh",
      "id": 33
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the first fantasy movie to win Best Picture at the Oscars?",
      "option": [
        "Harry Potter",
        "The Lord of the Rings: The Return of the King",
        "300"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "The Lord of the Rings: The Return of the King",
      "id": 34
    },
    {
      "question": "Who won Best Supporting Actor Oscars for both Moonlight and Green Book?",
      "option": ["Mahershala Ali", "Naomie Harris", "Viggo Mortensen"],
      "correctAnswer": "Mahershala Ali",
      "id": 35
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of the fictional boy band in Pixar's 2022 animation film - Turning Red?",
      "option": ["Cool boys", "4*Town", "New Kids on The block"],
      "correctAnswer": "4*Town",
      "id": 36
    },
    {
      "question": "How many angry men are there in the 1957 American courtroom drama film directed by Sidney Lumet?",
      "option": ["7", "10", "12"],
      "correctAnswer": "12",
      "id": 37
    },
    {
      "question": "After which movie did the sale of pet rats increase rapidly?",
      "option": ["Flushed Away", "Ratatouille", "Mouse Hunt"],
      "correctAnswer": " Ratatouille",
      "id": 38
    },
    {
      "question": "Name the 2015 film spinoff to the Rocky series starring Michael B. Jordan",
      "option": ["Just Mercy", "Creed", "Black Panther"],
      "correctAnswer": "Creed",
      "id": 39
    },
    {
      "question": "How many films have Kate Winslet and Leonardo DiCaprio starred in together?",
      "option": ["1", "2", "3"],
      "correctAnswer": "2",
      "id": 40
    },
    {
      "question": "Who plays king T'Challa in 2018 superhero film Black Panther?",
      "option": ["Michael B. Jordan", "Chadwick Boseman", "Daniel Kaluuya"],
      "correctAnswer": "Chadwick Boseman",
      "id": 41
    },
    {
      "question": "Whats the title of Daniel Craig's first James Bond film ?",
      "option": ["Specter", "Skyfall", "Quantum of Solace"],
      "correctAnswer": "Quantum of Solace",
      "id": 42
    },
    {
      "question": "‘Frankly my dear, I don’t give a damn’ is an iconic line from which classic film?",
      "option": ["All About Eve", "Strangers On a Train", "Gone With The Wind"],
      "correctAnswer": "Gone With The Wind",
      "id": 43
    },
    {
      "question": "What game does Rachel play with Nick's mom at the end of \"Crazy Rich Asians\"?",
      "option": ["Pin Pong", "Mahjong", "Chess"],
      "correctAnswer": "Mahjong",
      "id": 44
    },
    {
      "question": "Which actress plays Ryan Gosling's character's love interest in \"Crazy, Stupid, Love\"?",
      "option": ["Emma Stone", "Rachel Mcadams", "Jennifer Lawrence"],
      "correctAnswer": "Emma Stone",
      "id": 45
    },
    {
      "question": "What is Elle and Lee's favorite game in \"The Kissing Booth\"?",
      "option": ["Dance Dance Revolution", "Hula Hoop", "Kissing"],
      "correctAnswer": "Dance Dance Revolution",
      "id": 46
    },
    {
      "question": "Who destroys Thor's hammer?",
      "option": ["Loki", "Thanos", "Hela"],
      "correctAnswer": "Hela",
      "id": 47
    },
    {
      "question": "What metal is Wakanda's most precious resource?",
      "option": ["Iron", "Vibranium", "Steel"],
      "correctAnswer": "Vibranium",
      "id": 48
    },
    {
      "question": "Which James Bond movie was the first for Pierce Brosnan as 007?",
      "option": ["Die Another Day", "Tomorrow Never Comes", "Golden Eye"],
      "correctAnswer": "Golden Eye",
      "id": 49
    },
    {
      "question": "How many Oscars did the film Schindler’s List win?",
      "option": ["1", "4", "7"],
      "correctAnswer": "7",
      "id": 50
    },
    {
      "question": "Which Disney princess dresses up as a man to save her father?",
      "option": ["Jasmine", "Merida", "Mulan"],
      "correctAnswer": "Mulan",
      "id": 51
    },
    {
      "question": "What is Indiana Jones’ weapon of choice?",
      "option": ["A Gun", "A Sword", "A Whip"],
      "correctAnswer": "A Whip",
      "id": 52
    },
    {
      "question": "Who was the first solo female host of the Oscars?",
      "option": ["Demi Moore", "Whoopi Goldberg", "Julia Roberts"],
      "correctAnswer": "Whoopi Goldberg",
      "id": 53
    },
    {
      "question": "How many times has the movie A Star is Born been remade?",
      "option": ["2", "3", "4"],
      "correctAnswer": "4",
      "id": 54
    },
    {
      "question": "What does 'Dracarys' mean in Dothraki from the critical acclaim tv show Game of Thrones?",
      "option": ["Dragon Strike", "Dragon Fire", "Dragon Ice"],
      "correctAnswer": "Dragon Fire",
      "id": 55
    },
    {
      "question": "Who starred as Private Ryan in the movie Saving Private Ryan?",
      "option": ["Mark Wahlberg", "Matt Damon", "Tom Hanks"],
      "correctAnswer": "Matt Damon",
      "id": 56
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the youngest child’s name in the von Trapp family in the film The Sound of Music?",
      "option": ["Marta", "Gretl", "Brigitta"],
      "correctAnswer": "Gretl",
      "id": 57
    },
    {
      "question": "In which country was the classic musical The Sound of Music filmed ?",
      "option": ["Nazi Germany", "Austria", "Vienna"],
      "correctAnswer": "Austria",
      "id": 58
    },
    {
      "question": "How long did Forrest run in the film, Forrest Gump?",
      "option": [
        "3 years & 2 months",
        "3 years",
        "3 years, 2 months, 14 days, & 16 hours"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "3 years, 2 months, 14 days, & 16 hours",
      "id": 59
    },
    {
      "question": "In Back to the Future, what type of car is the time machine?",
      "option": [" Convertible", " Benz", " DeLorean"],
      "correctAnswer": " DeLorean",
      "id": 60
    },
    {
      "question": "Which 2018 film features the actor John Krasinski starring alongside his real-life wife, Emily Blunt?",
      "option": ["Fantastic Four", "A Quiet Place", "Girl On A Train"],
      "correctAnswer": "A Quiet Place",
      "id": 61
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of these actresses is not starring in the movie Hidden Figures ?",
      "option": ["Taraji P. Henson", "Janelle Monáe", "Viola Davis"],
      "correctAnswer": "Viola Davis",
      "id": 62
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of these actors portrayed the characters Randy Watson, Clarence and Saul in the 1988 classic comedy Coming To America ? ",
      "option": ["Arsenio Hall", "John Amos", "Eddie Murphy "],
      "correctAnswer": "Eddie Murphy ",
      "id": 63
    }
  ]
}
